<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GFESH - Global Foundation for Ethics &amp; Spiritual Health</title>
    <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on GFESH - Global Foundation for Ethics &amp; Spiritual Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2014 - 2017, GFESH; All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 13:50:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>GFESH 2017</title>
      <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2017/01/08/conf2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2017/01/08/conf2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gfesh-at-mumbai-january-08th-2017&#34;&gt;GFESH at Mumbai, January 08th, 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh2017&#34;&gt;GFES-2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GFESH 2016</title>
      <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2016/01/03/conf2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2016/01/03/conf2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gfesh-at-mumbai-january-03rd-2016&#34;&gt;GFESH at Mumbai, January 03rd, 2016&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GFESH 2015 Conference - USA</title>
      <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2015/06/21/conf2015-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2015/06/21/conf2015-usa/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gfesh-at-usa-june-21st-2015&#34;&gt;GFESH at USA, June 21st, 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GFESH 2014 Conference - USA</title>
      <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2014/07/20/conf2014-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2014/07/20/conf2014-usa/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gfesh-at-usa-july-20th-2014&#34;&gt;GFESH at USA, July 20th, 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GFESH 2014</title>
      <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2014/01/02/conf2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/blog/2014/01/02/conf2014/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gfesh-at-mumbai-january-02rd-2014&#34;&gt;GFESH at Mumbai, January 02rd, 2014&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;menu = &amp;quot;main&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AboutUs</title>
      <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/aboutus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/aboutus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Global Foundation for Ethics &amp;amp; Spiritual Health (GFESH) was established in 2014 with the single objective to bring science &amp;amp; spirituality together. GFESH is today playing an instrumental role in bringing medical &amp;amp; healthcare practitioners together to evolve a new holistic healthcare system based on ethical principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 21st Century healthcare needs a paradigm shift from focus on the treatment of disease to the promotion of wellness of communities, families and individuals that is patient-centered and community-based. Our society is today searching for holistic solutions to health which includes the mind, body and the soul. This kind of a healthcare system will always remain elusive if it is not based on the principles of medical &amp;amp; spiritual ethics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-our-objectives&#34;&gt;1. Our Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To bring science &amp;amp; spirituality together with the aim to provide holistic healthcare solutions encompassing the mind, body and soul.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help promote ethics and spiritual health in medical practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To shift focus from treatment of disease to wellness of communities, families and individuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-our-activites&#34;&gt;2. Our Activites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help establish a paradigm shift in 21st Century healthcare from a focus on the treatment of disease states to the promotion of wellness of communities, families and individuals that is patient-centered and community-based. To that end, we propose the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reincorporation of the traditional knowledge and spiritual science of healing into the modern science of healthcare – embracing body, mind, spirit with the closer involvement of medical community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoration of a healthy relationship with the nature , environment and natural way of living encompassing a holistic approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management of the treatment of disease with emphasis on lifestyle changes, with focus on behaviors and self-responsibility besides recoding the facts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of the effective and proven complementary and alternative disciplines of medicine and to encourage structured research in this direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposing transition from the current health care delivery model to one of collaboration, partnership and with deeper understanding of human needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the cost and improve outcomes in healthcare by bringing in mind set changes in health care delivery by incorporating the learnings in the medical and para medical education as proper structured curriculum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognition of a fundamental belief that Unconditional Love is life’s most powerful Healer and to study the correlation and effectiveness of counseling and such healing, on the patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-our-people&#34;&gt;3. Our People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;founder-members&#34;&gt;Founder Members:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radhanath Swami
HH Radhanath Swami is an internationally renowned spiritual guide, community builder, and the author of &amp;ldquo;The Journey Home: Autobiography of an American Swami&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous medical projects have been developed under his guidance in Mumbai, India, based on the ideal of Spirituality and Healing in Medicine, including the Bhaktivedanta Hospital, Barsana Eye Camp, and Vrindavan Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These projects are overseen by the Share Your Care Foundation, whose mission statement is:
&amp;ldquo;With love and devotion we will offer everyone a modern, scientific, holistic health-care service based on the true awareness and understanding of the needs of the body, mind and the soul.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radhanath Swami also directs numerous acclaimed social action projects, including eco-friendly farms, schools and ashrams, an orphanage, and emergency relief programs throughout India. He has recently met with President Obama, and spoken at the House of Lords in Parliament, HSBC headquarters, and the Milken Institute Global Conference.
Trustees &amp;amp; Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Alfred Ford
Alfred Ford is the great grandson of Henry Ford. The legendary senior Ford was also very interested in spirituality and believed in reincarnation. This influence was carried onto Mr. Alfred Ford, who was greatly inspired by a spiritual calling in his life. Continuing the legacy of his great grandfather, Mr. Ford along with his wife, Dr. Sharmila Bhattacharya, PhD, are visionary entrepreneurs and philanthropists with deep strategic interests in improving global health, particularly in the developing world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr H.A. MAFATLAL – Vice Chairman and Chief Executive, Arvind Mafatlal Group
Mr. Hrishikesh Arvind Mafatlal, serves as Chief Executive of the Arvind Mafatal Group of Companies. He was the President of the Millowners’ Association, Mumbai (MOA). He is a graduate of the Advanced Management Programme (AMP) at Harvard Business School. He continues in his late father&amp;rsquo;s philanthrophic footsteps, as he has been greatly moved and committed to various spiritual endeavors. He is the Chairman of the Bhaktivedanta Hospital and is an active supporter of numerous medical charitable projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;managing-committee&#34;&gt;Managing Committee:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Niketa Chotai - Singapore Chapter
MBBS, MD, DNB (India), FRCR(UK),
Fellowship in Breast Radiology (UFT, Canada)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a Consultant in Breast radiology at TTSH, Singapore
She is also a Senior Lecturer in YLL School of Medicine, National University of Singapore.
She has worked in wellness model of medicine and is a volunteer with Share Your Care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is trained in University of Toronto as subspecialist in Breast radiology and trained as Advanced specialist Trainee in Singapore&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puneet Kumar, MD, ABIHM - USA Chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Associate Attending,
Family &amp;amp; Occupational Medicine,
JFK Hospital, Edison, NJ &amp;amp;
Carrier Clinic, Belle Mead, NJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Puneet Kumar is a diplomate of the American Board of Family Medicine and the American Board of Integrative Holistic Medicine. With a background in Computer Science and Technology, he has spent the past 20 years exploring the common intersection of science, spirituality, consciousness, and the healing arts. He enthusiastically volunteers with projects sponsored by Share Your Care Foundation, including the Bhaktivedanta Hospital and annual Barsana Eye Cataract Surgery camp in India. He is spearheading the effort for the upcoming next event on June 21st in NJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-our-inspiration&#34;&gt;4. Our Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His Holiness Radhanath Swami is a Vaishnava sanyasi and teacher of the devotional path of Bhakti-yoga. He is author of The Journey Home a memoir of his search for spiritual truth. His teachings draw from the sacred texts of India such as The Bhagavad-gita, Srimad Bhagavatam, and Ramayana, and aim to reveal the practical application of the sacred traditions, while focusing on the shared essence, which unites apparently disparate religious or spiritual paths.
Born Richard Slavin, on December 7, 1950, in his teens he came to confront a deep sense of alienation from suburban Chicago life and the civil injustices of mid-century America. At the age of nineteen, while on a summer trip to Europe, his internal struggles culminated in a commitment to search for God wherever it might lead him. Meditating on the Isle of Crete, he felt a supernatural calling and the next morning set off alone to find spiritual India.
His book,“The Journey Home” documents his odyssey as a penniless hitchhiker though Greece, Turkey, Iran, Afghanistan, Pakistan and finally India. There he lived as a wandering ascetic, first amongst the forest dwelling Himalayan yogis and later amongst a wide variety of gurus and spiritual practitioners throughout India and Nepal. Ultimately, he was led to the holy town of Vrindavan, where he found his path amongst the Bhakti-yogis.
In Vrindavan he found the teacher he was searching for in A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada (1896-1977) the founder of the International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON), and representative of Gaudiya Vaishnavism. In choosing Bhaktivedanta Swami, as his guru, Radhanath Swami felt compelled to shear his matted locks and reenter Western society with a mission to share the sacred wisdom he had received. This return exemplifies the form of devotional yoga which is at the heart of Radhanath Swami’s teachings, a spiritual practice expressed as tangible action meant to bring about personal fulfillment and benefit the world.
At the the age of 31 he took the monastic vows of a Vaishnava sanyasi and became known as Radhanath Swami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today Radhanath Swami travels regularly throughout India, Europe and North America, sharing the teachings of Bhakti-yoga. He resides much of the year at the Radha Gopinath Ashram in Chowpatty, Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past twenty-five years he has guided the community’s development and has directed a number of acclaimed social action projects including Midday Meals, which daily serves more than 260,000 plates of sanctified vegetarian food to the children of the slums of Mumbai. He has also worked to establish missionary hospitals and eye camps, eco-friendly farms, schools and ashrams, an orphanage, and a number of emergency relief programs throughout India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HIS BESTSELLING BOOK – THE JOURNEY HOME&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within this extraordinary memoir, Radhanath Swami weaves a colorful tapestry of adventure, mysticism, and love. Readers follow Richard Slavin from the suburbs of Chicago to the caves of the Himalayas as he transforms from young seeker to renowned spiritual guide.
The Journey Home is an intimate account of the steps to self awareness and a penetrating glimpse into the heart of mystic traditions and the challenges that all souls must face on the road to inner harmony and a union with the Divine. Through near-death encounters, apprenticeships with advanced yogis, and years of travel along the pilgrim’s path, Radhanath Swami eventually reaches the inner sanctum of India’s mystic culture and finds the love he has been seeking. It is a tale told with rare candor, immersing the reader in a journey that is at once engaging, humorous, and heartwarming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/contact/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;together-we-can&#34;&gt;Together we can&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in working with us or just curious to know more about us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to contact us. We will try to get back asap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Membership</title>
      <link>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kstsvcs.github.io/gfesh/membership/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;would-be-launched-during-gfesh-2017&#34;&gt;Would be launched during GFESH 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>